# Dr. Vladimir O. Talibov

Last update: March 19, 2020

Neversvägen 43 SE 22479 Lund, Sweden +460728453329 vladimir.o.talibov@gmail.com http://vtalibov.xyz

# **Summary**

A protein chemist with an interest in early stage drug discovery. Experienced in biosensors, general biophysical techniques and enzymology. Keen to set up new expertises and methodologies that are required for a successful project development.

## Skills

Experimental: Biophysical methods (SPR, MST, TSA), protein techniques, expression&purification, enzymology, macromolecular crystallography.

 $\underline{\textit{Computer:}} \ *nix, \ T_E\!X, \ crystallographic \ suites, \ KNIME.$ 

Languages: English, Russian, Swedish(basic).

Expertise: FBLD, early-stage drug design, biophysical methods, protein chemistry.

## Experience

#### Researcher

2019 - current

MAX IV laboratory, Lund, Sweden

- Beamline development and user support as a beamline scientist.
- Design, maintenance and curation of in-house fragment library; development of operational protocols for MAX IV fragment screening facility.

Laboratory Assistant

2012 - 2014

OOO "Biochip-IMB", Moscow, Russia

- Clinical chemistry: development and benchmarking of protein microarray-based diagnostic assays.
- QC of proteins and reactive small molecules.

### Education

#### PhD in Biochemistry

2014 - 2019

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

Biophysical methods.

Thesis: "Interaction kinetic analysis in drug design, enzymology and protein research".

BSc&MSc in Chemistry

2008 - 2013

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

Specialisation in bioorganic chemistry, thesis in bioanalytical chemistry.

## Interests

Methods for FBLD, drug design, biophysical methods.

#### **Publications**

- J. Yang\*, V. O. Talibov\*, S. Peintner, C. Rhee, V. Poongavanam, M. Geitmann, M. R. Sebastiano, B. Simon, J. Hennig, D. Dobritzsch, U. H. Danielson, and J. Kihlberg. "Macrocyclic Peptides Uncover a Novel Binding Mode for Reversible Inhibitors of LSD1". In: ACS omega 8.5 (2020), pp. 3979–3995.
- [2] E. Fabini\*, V. O. Talibov\*, F. Mihalic, M. Naldi, M. Bartolini, C. Bertucci, A. Del Rio, and U. H. Danielson. "Unveiling the biochemistry of the epigenetic regulator SMYD3". In: *Biochemistry* 58.35 (2019), pp. 3634–3645.
- [3] V. O. Talibov, V. Linkuvienė, U. H. Danielson, and D. Matulis. "Kinetic Analysis of Carbonic Anhydrase–Sulfonamide Inhibitor Interactions". In: *Carbonic Anhydrase as Drug Target*. Springer, Cham, 2019, pp. 125–140.
- [4] V. Linkuviene\*, V. O. Talibov\*, U. H. Danielson, and D. Matulis. "Introduction of intrinsic kinetics of protein–ligand interactions and their implications for drug design". In: *J. Med. Chem.* 61.6 (2018), pp. 2292–2302.
- [5] C. Seeger, V. O. Talibov, and U. H. Danielson. "Biophysical analysis of the dynamics of calmodulin interactions with neurogranin and Ca2+/calmodulin-dependent kinase II". In: J. Mol. Recognit. 30.8 (2017), e2621.
- [6] V. O. Talibov, V. Linkuvienė, D. Matulis, and U. H. Danielson. "Kinetically selective inhibitors of human carbonic anhydrase isozymes I, II, VII, IX, XII, and XIII". In: J. Med. Chem. 59.5 (2016), pp. 2083–2093.
- [7] V. I. Butvilovskaya, M. V. Tsybulskaya, A. A. Tikhonov, V. O. Talibov, P. V. Belousov, A. Y. Sazykin, A. M. Schwartz, S. A. Surzhikov, A. A. Stomakhin, O. N. Solopova, et al. "Preparation of recombinant serpins B3 and B4 and investigation of their specific interactions with antibodies using hydrogel-based microarrays". In: *Mol. Biol.* 49.5 (2015), pp. 705–713.
- [8] B. Koos, G. Cane, K. Grannas, L. Löf, L. Arngården, J. Heldin, C.-M. Clausson, A. Klaesson, M. K. Hirvonen, F. M. De Oliveira, et al. "Proximity-dependent initiation of hybridization chain reaction". In: Nat. Commun. 6 (2015), p. 7294.
- [9] G. U. Feyzkhanova, M. A. Filippova, V. O. Talibov, E. I. Dementieva, V. V. Maslennikov, Y. P. Reznikov, N. Offermann, A. S. Zasedatelev, A. Y. Rubina, and M. Fooke-Achterrath. "Development of hydrogel biochip for in vitro allergy diagnostics". In: *J. Immunol. Methods* 406 (2014), pp. 51–57.
- [10] A. Y. Rubina, G. U. Feizkhanova, M. A. Filippova, V. O. Talibov, M. Fooke-Achterrath, and A. S. Zasedatelev. "Multiplex assay of allergen-specific and total immunoglobulins of E and G classes in the biochip format". In: *Dokl. Biochem. Biophys.* 447.1 (2012), p. 289.